<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-09-04T17:19:52+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Najm Us Saqib’s Personal Website</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A few changes to the website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/08/08/newblog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A few changes to the website" /><published>2023-08-08T22:03:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-08-08T22:03:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/08/08/newblog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/08/08/newblog.html"><![CDATA[<p>I have started reworking to my two sites that I started in early 2022. I learned the Jekyll static website builder and rewritten the whole website using Jekyll. This website and the wiki of ‘One Hundred Years of Solitude’ was build page by page copy pasting same code everytime I had to make another page. This was a painful experience and was actually regressive.</p>

<p>With jekyll I don’t have to write the same code again and again, and its quite productive as well. I have rebuilt this site in no time retaining the same theme that was being used before. Some new features added in the website is a blog and the design is responsive.</p>

<p>I am currently working on the other website which is very difficult task because it has many pages. Every character has its own page and a lots of info. Before Jekyll making this site was a nightmare, but now I can use some of the cool features of Jekyll to pace things up. Really hoping to complete the site soon. Wish me luck.</p>]]></content><author><name>Saqib</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have started reworking to my two sites that I started in early 2022. I learned the Jekyll static website builder and rewritten the whole website using Jekyll. This website and the wiki of ‘One Hundred Years of Solitude’ was build page by page copy pasting same code everytime I had to make another page. This was a painful experience and was actually regressive. With jekyll I don’t have to write the same code again and again, and its quite productive as well. I have rebuilt this site in no time retaining the same theme that was being used before. Some new features added in the website is a blog and the design is responsive. I am currently working on the other website which is very difficult task because it has many pages. Every character has its own page and a lots of info. Before Jekyll making this site was a nightmare, but now I can use some of the cool features of Jekyll to pace things up. Really hoping to complete the site soon. Wish me luck.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Complete rewriting the website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/08/04/rewriting-the-website.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Complete rewriting the website" /><published>2023-08-04T15:04:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-08-04T15:04:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/08/04/rewriting-the-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/08/04/rewriting-the-website.html"><![CDATA[<p>I am rewriting this whole website in the new website builder called jekyll. This is a new experience and I am learning a lot. This approach of building websites is totally different from how I previously build websites. In this way I don’t have to copy or write repetitive code again and again rather ‘jekyll’ applies the same code to all pages with the same layout. This saves a whole lot of time.</p>

<p>A lot of work has to be done in the website to make it look complete, however a website is never complete. Anyways, developin is very fun because, firstly I am learning something new doing it, secondly I am getting a chance to revamp my site for more functionality. I am looking forward to integrating a lot of other things in this website which I hope be evem more interesting. I also hope you will enjoy your time being on my site becuse a lot of content is going to be added in the nooks and corner of this site to find by the visitors.</p>

<p>I hope you enjoy.</p>

<p>take care. adios.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am rewriting this whole website in the new website builder called jekyll. This is a new experience and I am learning a lot. This approach of building websites is totally different from how I previously build websites. In this way I don’t have to copy or write repetitive code again and again rather ‘jekyll’ applies the same code to all pages with the same layout. This saves a whole lot of time. A lot of work has to be done in the website to make it look complete, however a website is never complete. Anyways, developin is very fun because, firstly I am learning something new doing it, secondly I am getting a chance to revamp my site for more functionality. I am looking forward to integrating a lot of other things in this website which I hope be evem more interesting. I also hope you will enjoy your time being on my site becuse a lot of content is going to be added in the nooks and corner of this site to find by the visitors. I hope you enjoy. take care. adios.]]></summary></entry></feed>