<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-04-06T00:49:09+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Najm Us Saqib’s Personal Website</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Experiences While Making a CV Website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/01/05/cv.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Experiences While Making a CV Website" /><published>2024-01-05T00:09:00+05:30</published><updated>2024-01-05T00:09:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/01/05/cv</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/01/05/cv.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, recently I have taken to creating multiple websites, which include a daily journal which is heavily a work in progress and the second one is my CV.<!--more--> Creating a single-page CV website was not a challenging task unto itself, but making it through an <abbr title="Static Site Generetor">SSG</abbr> was kind of a bump in a road. You see, writing vanilla HTML is boring and repetitive, by using an SSG we can automate the repeating code and just write the main content. Since, I am learning to work with Jekyll, so I thought I’d give it a try.</p>

<p>When I started writing, I started by manually writing all the information, my details and everything, but just then I though wait, I can automate this as well. I thought of a thing called ‘data files’. Using ‘data files’ you can store data in a separate file and then render those data in the HTML. By this you need not write code every time you enter some new detail, rather you just enter the specific data in the data files, and it will be automatically generated for you.</p>

<p>For example, let’s say my CV has a section which lists all the internships I’ve done till date, so I entered the list in the code like this</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-html" data-lang="html"><span class="nt">&lt;ul&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;li&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;strong&gt;</span>Name:<span class="nt">&lt;/strong&gt;</span>Internship 1 <span class="nt">&lt;br&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;strong&gt;</span>details:<span class="nt">&lt;/strong&gt;</span>details regarding the internship <span class="nt">&lt;br&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;strong&gt;</span>details:<span class="nt">&lt;/strong&gt;</span>more details 
<span class="nt">&lt;/li&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;/ul&gt;</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>But after using ‘data files’ I can write as little as just.</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-yaml" data-lang="yaml"><span class="pi">-</span> <span class="na">Name</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s1">'</span><span class="s">Internship</span><span class="nv"> </span><span class="s">1'</span>
  <span class="na">details</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">details of the internship</span>
  <span class="na">details</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">more details</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Now while these benefits exist, another pros is even important which is the readability of the document, I mean if I write a long HTML document it is going to be a disaster if I need to make some changes in the future. For simplicity’s sake, using ‘data files’ was the best way to go. In Jekyll, I made a ‘YAML’ file and put all my details there, and then wrote code in the index.html to render the data in the webpage. So, now with as little code as possible and without repeating the same code, I can display all my details.</p>

<p>Another thing I did was, instead of writing my own CSS to style the webpage, I turned my head towards the CSS frameworks. The CSS frameworks are basically pre-written code (which are fashionably called boilerplate code) which you can use in your website without having to write all the same code yourself. The frameworks are a great way of saving time, because why waste time writing some code which has already been written by numerous people.</p>

<p>After several hours of work, I finally managed to create a website which looks good and is minimal. However, I am still thinking about changing font and several minor improvements, otherwise the website is ready.</p>

<p>Here, you can have a look - <a href="https://twisthead.github.io/curriculum-vitae/">CV</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Nazm Us Saqib</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, recently I have taken to creating multiple websites, which include a daily journal which is heavily a work in progress and the second one is my CV.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Easiest way to add pagination in Jekyll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/12/09/adding-pagination-in-jekyll-site.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Easiest way to add pagination in Jekyll" /><published>2023-12-09T10:37:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-12-09T10:37:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/12/09/adding-pagination-in-jekyll-site</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/12/09/adding-pagination-in-jekyll-site.html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I was thinking of adding pagination to my site, and it turned out to be a nighmare. <!--more--> I had to google so many things and waste so much time. After spending considerable amount of time researching, I got it working finally.</p>

<p>The pagination in Jekyll is difficult and it is incomprehensively documented on Jekyll Docs, which makes it pretty difficult to add pagination to the site. Here I am aiming to sum up numerous tutorials which helped me add pagination to my site.</p>

<p>Follow along and do exactly what’s stated and you’ll have the pagination.</p>

<p><strong>1. Install required gems</strong></p>

<p>You need to install the plugin <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">"jekyll-pagination"</code>.</p>

<p><strong>Edit “config.yml” &amp; “gemfile” file</strong></p>

<p>Add the follwing lines in ‘config.yml’</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-yaml" data-lang="yaml"><span class="na">plugins</span><span class="pi">:</span>
    <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="s">jekyll-paginate</span>

<span class="na">paginate</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="m">5</span>
<span class="na">paginate-path</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s2">"</span><span class="s">/blog/page:num/"</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>It should look something like this</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><img src="/assets/ss-for-blog/plugin.png" alt="code" /></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Add the following line to “gemfile” located in the root directory.</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-yaml" data-lang="yaml"><span class="c1"># place it just below the line "group :jekyll_plugins do"</span>

<span class="s">gem "jekyll-paginate"</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>It should look something like this.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><img src="/assets/ss-for-blog/gemfile.png" alt="gemfile" /></p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>Open a terminal, navigate to your directory and run the command.</li>
</ul>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="c"># run in terminal</span>

bundle <span class="nb">install</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Now you are done with half of the work.</p>

<p><strong>2. Making a page where you list your blogs.</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Make a folder called “blog” in project’s root directory.</li>
  <li>Inside the folder make a file called “index.html”.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>3. Put the below code to generate list of posts with pagination.</strong></p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-html" data-lang="html">---
layout: default
title: My Blog
---

<span class="c">&lt;!-- This loops through the paginated posts --&gt;</span>
{% for post in paginator.posts %}
  <span class="nt">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a</span> <span class="na">href=</span><span class="s">"{{ post.url }}"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>{{ post.title }}<span class="nt">&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;</span>
  <span class="nt">&lt;p</span> <span class="na">class=</span><span class="s">"author"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>
    <span class="nt">&lt;span</span> <span class="na">class=</span><span class="s">"date"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>{{ post.date }}<span class="nt">&lt;/span&gt;</span>
  <span class="nt">&lt;/p&gt;</span>
  <span class="nt">&lt;div</span> <span class="na">class=</span><span class="s">"content"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>
    {{ post.content }}
  <span class="nt">&lt;/div&gt;</span>
{% endfor %}

<span class="c">&lt;!-- Pagination links --&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;div</span> <span class="na">class=</span><span class="s">"pagination"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>
  {% if paginator.previous_page %}
    <span class="nt">&lt;a</span> <span class="na">href=</span><span class="s">"{{ paginator.previous_page_path }}"</span> <span class="na">class=</span><span class="s">"previous"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>
      Previous
    <span class="nt">&lt;/a&gt;</span>
  {% else %}
    <span class="nt">&lt;span</span> <span class="na">class=</span><span class="s">"previous"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>Previous<span class="nt">&lt;/span&gt;</span>
  {% endif %}
  <span class="nt">&lt;span</span> <span class="na">class=</span><span class="s">"page_number "</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>
    Page: {{ paginator.page }} of {{ paginator.total_pages }}
  <span class="nt">&lt;/span&gt;</span>
  {% if paginator.next_page %}
    <span class="nt">&lt;a</span> <span class="na">href=</span><span class="s">"{{ paginator.next_page_path }}"</span> <span class="na">class=</span><span class="s">"next"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>Next<span class="nt">&lt;/a&gt;</span>
  {% else %}
    <span class="nt">&lt;span</span> <span class="na">class=</span><span class="s">"next "</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>Next<span class="nt">&lt;/span&gt;</span>
  {% endif %}
<span class="nt">&lt;/div&gt;</span></code></pre></figure>

<p><strong>Now you have your paginated post.</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Not successfull?
    <ol>
      <li>Make sure there’s no typo in any of the  entries.</li>
      <li>Make sure you executed every command.</li>
      <li>Comment your issue.</li>
    </ol>
  </li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Nazm Us Saqib</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently I was thinking of adding pagination to my site, and it turned out to be a nighmare.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Web Apps can actually help grow Linux</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/11/03/how-desktop-apps-can-help-linux.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Web Apps can actually help grow Linux" /><published>2023-11-03T19:48:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-11-03T19:48:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/11/03/how-desktop-apps-can-help-linux</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/11/03/how-desktop-apps-can-help-linux.html"><![CDATA[<p>I am a very passionate Linux user, and I appreciate the philosophy that works behind the “Free Software” and “Open Source Initiative”.<!--more--> Linux in the computing world acts as an equivalent to the opposition parties in a democracy. In a democracy, an opposition party is needed to keep the ruling party in check. Just like in the computing world, the ruling party is the big tech companies that enjoy a large market share of their products. Linux (or any alternative OS to Windows and macOS such as FreeBSD, Haiku, etc.) keeps checking on the operating systems that have a larger market share. Users always have the option to move away from the operating system they are currently using if they are not satisfied with the services. Linux provides that option. However, many users can’t make the change because of the unavailability of software and apps for Linux. A lot of software developers do not make their software compatible with Linux because the market share is comparatively lower than that of mainstream operating systems.</p>

<p>The thesis argument of this blog is that “how could the web apps help popularise and make easy the move to Linux for the users?” As we move closer to making the web capable of doing almost all things natively on PCs, More and more software companies are providing web apps for their software, like Adobe Photoshop, which does not have a Linux version of their software. So, the user can actually use the web version of Photoshop on Linux as it can on Windows or macOS. Linux supports browsers and performs natively with web apps, and in many cases, it performs way better than Windows. With the growing popularity of web apps, it is going to be immensely easy for those users who hesitate to migrate because the software they work on does not support Linux.</p>

<p>This is an excellent thing for Linux as well, not because it can garner more profit from the increase in users. Rather, it will be good because more people will come to know how good the Linux operating system is, regardless of the myth that it is only for tech enthusiasts.</p>]]></content><author><name>Nazm Us Saqib</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am a very passionate Linux user, and I appreciate the philosophy that works behind the “Free Software” and “Open Source Initiative”.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A few changes to the website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/08/08/newblog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A few changes to the website" /><published>2023-08-08T22:03:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-08-08T22:03:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/08/08/newblog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/08/08/newblog.html"><![CDATA[<p>I have started reworking to my two sites that I started in early 2022. I learned the Jekyll static website builder and rewritten the whole website using Jekyll. <!--more--> This website and the wiki of ‘One Hundred Years of Solitude’ was build page by page copy pasting same code every time I had to make another page. This was a painful experience and was actually regressive.</p>

<p>With Jekyll I don’t have to write the same code again and again, and its quite productive as well. I have rebuilt this site in no time retaining the same theme that was being used before. Some new features added in the website is a blog and the design is responsive.</p>

<p>I am currently working on the other website which is very difficult task because it has many pages. Every character has its own page and a lots of info. Before Jekyll making this site was a nightmare, but now I can use some of the cool features of Jekyll to pace things up. Really hoping to complete the site soon. Wish me luck.</p>]]></content><author><name>Nazm Us Saqib</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have started reworking to my two sites that I started in early 2022. I learned the Jekyll static website builder and rewritten the whole website using Jekyll.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Complete rewriting the website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/08/04/rewriting-the-website.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Complete rewriting the website" /><published>2023-08-04T15:04:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-08-04T15:04:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/08/04/rewriting-the-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/08/04/rewriting-the-website.html"><![CDATA[<p>I am rewriting this whole website in the new website builder called Jekyll.<!--more--> This is a new experience and I am learning a lot. This approach of building websites is totally different from how I previously build websites. In this way I don’t have to copy or write repetitive code again and again rather ‘Jekyll’ applies the same code to all pages with the same layout. This saves a whole lot of time.</p>

<p>A lot of work has to be done in the website to make it look complete, however a website is never complete. Anyway, developing is very fun because, firstly I am learning something new doing it, secondly I am getting a chance to revamp my site for more functionality. I am looking forward to integrating a lot of other things in this website which I hope be even more interesting. I also hope you will enjoy your time being on my site because a lot of content is going to be added in the nooks and corner of this site to find by the visitors.</p>

<p>I hope you enjoy.</p>

<p>take care. adios.</p>]]></content><author><name>Nazm Us Saqib</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am rewriting this whole website in the new website builder called Jekyll.]]></summary></entry></feed>