<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-11-09T22:16:07+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Najm Us Saqib’s Personal Website</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How Web Apps can actually help grow Linux</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/11/03/how-desktop-apps-can-help-linux.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Web Apps can actually help grow Linux" /><published>2023-11-03T19:48:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-11-03T19:48:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/11/03/how-desktop-apps-can-help-linux</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/11/03/how-desktop-apps-can-help-linux.html"><![CDATA[<p>I am a very passionate Linux user, and I appreciate the philosophy that works behind the “Free Software” and “Open Source Initiative”. Linux in the computing world acts as an equivalent to the opposition parties in a democracy. In a democracy, an opposition party is needed to keep the ruling party in check. Just like in the computing world, the ruling party is the big tech companies that enjoy a large market share of their products. Linux (or any alternative OS to Windows and macOS such as FreeBSD, Haiku, etc.) keeps checking on the operating systems that have a larger market share. Users always have the option to move away from the operating system they are currently using if they are not satisfied with the services. Linux provides that option. However, many users can’t make the change because of the unavailability of software and apps for Linux. A lot of software developers do not make their software compatible with Linux because the market share is comparatively lower than that of mainstream operating systems.</p>

<p>The thesis argument of this blog is that “how could the web apps help popularise and make easy the move to Linux for the users?” As we move closer to making the web capable of doing almost all things natively on PCs, More and more software companies are providing web apps for their software, like Adobe Photoshop, which does not have a Linux version of their software. So, the user can actually use the web version of Photoshop on Linux as it can on Windows or macOS. Linux supports browsers and performs natively with web apps, and in many cases, it performs way better than Windows. With the growing popularity of web apps, it is going to be immensely easy for those users who hesitate to migrate because the software they work on does not support Linux.</p>

<p>This is an excellent thing for Linux as well, not because it can garner more profit from the increase in users. Rather, it will be good because more people will come to know how good the Linux operating system is, regardless of the myth that it is only for tech enthusiasts.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am a very passionate Linux user, and I appreciate the philosophy that works behind the “Free Software” and “Open Source Initiative”. Linux in the computing world acts as an equivalent to the opposition parties in a democracy. In a democracy, an opposition party is needed to keep the ruling party in check. Just like in the computing world, the ruling party is the big tech companies that enjoy a large market share of their products. Linux (or any alternative OS to Windows and macOS such as FreeBSD, Haiku, etc.) keeps checking on the operating systems that have a larger market share. Users always have the option to move away from the operating system they are currently using if they are not satisfied with the services. Linux provides that option. However, many users can’t make the change because of the unavailability of software and apps for Linux. A lot of software developers do not make their software compatible with Linux because the market share is comparatively lower than that of mainstream operating systems. The thesis argument of this blog is that “how could the web apps help popularise and make easy the move to Linux for the users?” As we move closer to making the web capable of doing almost all things natively on PCs, More and more software companies are providing web apps for their software, like Adobe Photoshop, which does not have a Linux version of their software. So, the user can actually use the web version of Photoshop on Linux as it can on Windows or macOS. Linux supports browsers and performs natively with web apps, and in many cases, it performs way better than Windows. With the growing popularity of web apps, it is going to be immensely easy for those users who hesitate to migrate because the software they work on does not support Linux. This is an excellent thing for Linux as well, not because it can garner more profit from the increase in users. Rather, it will be good because more people will come to know how good the Linux operating system is, regardless of the myth that it is only for tech enthusiasts.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A few changes to the website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/08/08/newblog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A few changes to the website" /><published>2023-08-08T22:03:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-08-08T22:03:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/08/08/newblog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/08/08/newblog.html"><![CDATA[<p>I have started reworking to my two sites that I started in early 2022. I learned the Jekyll static website builder and rewritten the whole website using Jekyll. This website and the wiki of ‘One Hundred Years of Solitude’ was build page by page copy pasting same code every time I had to make another page. This was a painful experience and was actually regressive.</p>

<p>With Jekyll I don’t have to write the same code again and again, and its quite productive as well. I have rebuilt this site in no time retaining the same theme that was being used before. Some new features added in the website is a blog and the design is responsive.</p>

<p>I am currently working on the other website which is very difficult task because it has many pages. Every character has its own page and a lots of info. Before Jekyll making this site was a nightmare, but now I can use some of the cool features of Jekyll to pace things up. Really hoping to complete the site soon. Wish me luck.</p>]]></content><author><name>Saqib</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have started reworking to my two sites that I started in early 2022. I learned the Jekyll static website builder and rewritten the whole website using Jekyll. This website and the wiki of ‘One Hundred Years of Solitude’ was build page by page copy pasting same code every time I had to make another page. This was a painful experience and was actually regressive. With Jekyll I don’t have to write the same code again and again, and its quite productive as well. I have rebuilt this site in no time retaining the same theme that was being used before. Some new features added in the website is a blog and the design is responsive. I am currently working on the other website which is very difficult task because it has many pages. Every character has its own page and a lots of info. Before Jekyll making this site was a nightmare, but now I can use some of the cool features of Jekyll to pace things up. Really hoping to complete the site soon. Wish me luck.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Complete rewriting the website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/08/04/rewriting-the-website.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Complete rewriting the website" /><published>2023-08-04T15:04:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-08-04T15:04:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/08/04/rewriting-the-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/08/04/rewriting-the-website.html"><![CDATA[<p>I am rewriting this whole website in the new website builder called Jekyll. This is a new experience and I am learning a lot. This approach of building websites is totally different from how I previously build websites. In this way I don’t have to copy or write repetitive code again and again rather ‘Jekyll’ applies the same code to all pages with the same layout. This saves a whole lot of time.</p>

<p>A lot of work has to be done in the website to make it look complete, however a website is never complete. Anyway, developing is very fun because, firstly I am learning something new doing it, secondly I am getting a chance to revamp my site for more functionality. I am looking forward to integrating a lot of other things in this website which I hope be even more interesting. I also hope you will enjoy your time being on my site because a lot of content is going to be added in the nooks and corner of this site to find by the visitors.</p>

<p>I hope you enjoy.</p>

<p>take care. adios.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am rewriting this whole website in the new website builder called Jekyll. This is a new experience and I am learning a lot. This approach of building websites is totally different from how I previously build websites. In this way I don’t have to copy or write repetitive code again and again rather ‘Jekyll’ applies the same code to all pages with the same layout. This saves a whole lot of time. A lot of work has to be done in the website to make it look complete, however a website is never complete. Anyway, developing is very fun because, firstly I am learning something new doing it, secondly I am getting a chance to revamp my site for more functionality. I am looking forward to integrating a lot of other things in this website which I hope be even more interesting. I also hope you will enjoy your time being on my site because a lot of content is going to be added in the nooks and corner of this site to find by the visitors. I hope you enjoy. take care. adios.]]></summary></entry></feed>